# Ivan Alejandro Hernandez Aguirre, Controls / Data Science Engineer

Controls Engineer currently transitioning to Data Science, during my work experience I have done projects in Canada, USA, Mexico and Argentina. Used to thrive on high pressure scenarios thanks to a high adaptability, and patience.

Mental agility, flexibility with challenges and constant changes.

Fast learning, high sense of urgency and hard working skills/

#### **Employment History**

## Controls Engineer at Data Realm Inc, Windsor

August 2015 — March 2017

Mostly involved in Autocad Design and Development of HMI using Visu +, Wonderware and Factory Talk for Honda and Ford

### Controls Engineer at Level One Robotics, Windsor Ontario

March 2017 — April 2019

Involved in the design, troubleshooting, debugging and programming of assembly lines, database setups, hardware setup for customers such as Ford, Tesla and Flex N Gate.

# Lead Controls/ Contractor Engineer at AIS, Chrysler and HAD, Several Locations

April 2019 — May 2022

Involved in design, installation, programming, setup of hardware and database with OPC, buy off for several customer:

Lead Controls Engineer at customer installation Flex N Gate Argentina.

Lead Controls Engineer at Chrysler Etobicoke for shocktower installation project.

Support and Debugging for General Motors at Oshawa, Ontario

#### Education

# Mechatronics Bachelors Degree, Instituto Tecnologico de Durango, Durango

August 2011 — August 2015

#### Python Certificate, eCornell University, Toronto

August 2021 — December 2022

#### Links

#### Linkedin

Skills	0	Teamwork	0	Communication
	0	Ability to Work Under Pressure	0	Leadership and Teamwork
	0	Analytical Skills	0	Decision Making
	0	PLC programming Allen Bradley	0	HMI Development
	0	Database connection	0	FANUC Robots Troubleshooting
	0	Debugging	0	Data Analysis
	0	SQL , Pandas	0	Matpotlib ,seaborn and other libraries
	0	Siemens and Omron PLC	0	Data Cleaning and wrangling
	0	Create Models Data Science	0	OPC Server setup
	0	Hardware setup for assembly lines	0	Factory Talk Development
Languages	0	English Highly proficient	0	Spanish; Castilian Native speaker